[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Which of the following sentence is correct?",
    "options": [
      "I forbad him from going",
      "I forbad him not to go",
      "I forbad him going",
      "I forbade him to go"
    ],
    "answer": "I forbade him to go"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following is a correct proverb?",
    "options": [
      "Fools rush in where the angels fear to tread.",
      "A fool rushes in where an angel fears to tread",
      "Fools rush in where an angel fear to tread",
      "Fools rush in where angels fear to tread"
    ],
    "answer": "Fools rush in where angels fear to tread"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following sentence is correct?",
    "options": [
      "Why you have done this",
      "Why have you done this",
      "Why did you have done this",
      "Why you had done this"
    ],
    "answer": "Why have you done this"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which of the following sentence is correct?",
    "options": [
      "The shirt which he bought is blue in colour",
      "Which shirt he bought is blue in colour",
      "That shirt which he bought is blue in colour",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "The shirt which he bought is blue in colour"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The correct passive of 'Sheila was writing a letter' is-",
    "options": [
      "A letter was being written by Sheila",
      "A letter was being was being written by Sheila",
      "A letter was being writing by Sheila",
      "A letter was written by Sheila"
    ],
    "answer": "A letter was being written by Sheila"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which of the following sentences is correct?",
    "options": [
      "One of my friends are a lawyers",
      "One of my friend is a lawyer",
      "One of my friends are a lawyer",
      "One of my friends is a lawyer"
    ],
    "answer": "One of my friends is a lawyer"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The word 'Ecological' is related to-",
    "options": ["Atmosphere", "Pollution", "Environment", "Demography"],
    "answer": "Environment"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "The synonym of 'Genesis' is-",
    "options": ["Beginning", "Preface", "Introduction", "Foreword"],
    "answer": "Beginning"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The word 'Homogeneous' means-",
    "options": [
      "Of the same place",
      "Of the same kind",
      "Of the same race",
      "Of the same density"
    ],
    "answer": "Of the same kind"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The word 'Imbibe' means-",
    "options": ["To tinge", "To drink", "To acquire", "To learn"],
    "answer": "To drink"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Something which is Obnoxious means that it is?",
    "options": [
      "very dangerous",
      "very pleasant",
      "very ugly",
      "very unpleasant"
    ],
    "answer": "very unpleasant"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "A pilgrim is a person who undertakes a journey to a",
    "options": ["a mosque", "holy place", "a bazar", "a new country"],
    "answer": "holy place"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Shakespeare is known mostly for his-",
    "options": ["novels", "autobiography", "plays", "poetry"],
    "answer": "plays"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "A person who writes about his own life writes-",
    "options": ["a chronicle", "an autobiography", "a diary", "a biography"],
    "answer": "an autobiography"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "In which century was the Victorian period?",
    "options": ["19th century", "20th century", "18th century", "17th century"],
    "answer": "19th century"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "The antonym of 'Indifference' is-",
    "options": ["Ardour", "collision", "Anxiety", "Conclusion"],
    "answer": "Ardour"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Three score is",
    "options": [
      "Three times twenty",
      "More than three",
      "Three hundred times",
      "Thirty times"
    ],
    "answer": "Three times twenty"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "An ordinance is-",
    "options": ["A book", "An arms factory", "A newspaper journal", "A law"],
    "answer": "A law"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "A fantasy is?",
    "options": [
      "A funny film",
      "An imaginary story",
      "A history record",
      "A real life event"
    ],
    "answer": "An imaginary story"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Something that is fresh is something-",
    "options": [
      "Recently printed or published",
      "Disrespectful",
      "In fairly good condition",
      "Pleasant"
    ],
    "answer": "In fairly good condition"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Intellectual শব্দের বাংলা অর্থ-",
    "options": ["বুদ্ধিমান", "মননশীল", "বুদ্ধিজীবি", "মেধাবী"],
    "answer": "বুদ্ধিজীবি"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Straw vote বলতে কি বুঝায়?",
    "options": [
      "Manipulated elections",
      "Yes-no vote",
      "Poll based on random representations",
      "Unofficial poll of public opinion"
    ],
    "answer": "Unofficial poll of public opinion"
  }
]
